GANJAR VILLANUEVA

Apt Grand Emerald 16WH, Kelapa Gading, Jakarta Utara, Indonesia | ganjarv@gmail.com | Mobile: +62 878 2431 6962 |

OBJECTIVES

IT Professional with a solid business management educational background and 10 years of experiences on project management in IT industry, corporate innovation, design thinking, business process management. My previous experiences in technical, managerial aspect and business process gave me a proficiency and expertise identifying and mitigate risk and also with strengthen my extensive experiences dealing with local and global customers also understanding their business needs. My valuable experiences in both technical and managerial aspect, together with the highly self-driven, proactive and resilient personality will be a valuable asset to your company.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Master of Information Technology (MInfTech), 2012 University of Technology Sydney, Sydney, Australia

Bachelor of Economic (SE) in Business Management, 2006 University of Padjajaran, Bandung, Indonesia

KEY SKILLS

- **△ Project Management**
- A Team work player and independent.
- Ability to work efficient and effectively.
- **△** Communicate effectively with range of staff and customer.
- **△** Ability to work under pressure.
- ▲ Languages: English and Indonesian.

- Ability to work with computer.
 - ✓ Web Development:
 - Html5&CSS3
 - Boostrap4
 - Javascript, JQuery, Node.js & Express.js
 - API
 - Wordpress
 - ✓ MS-Office Application
 - ✓ Axure, Balsimiq (wireframe & prototype design tool)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PT. GIB (Gemilang Inovasi Bangsa)

10/2017 to 01/2019

Co-Founder

- Identifying market opportunities or areas where consumers may want or need a product that does not yet exist.
- Preparing product development, determining specifications, and bring product into production.
- Developing financial forecast and set milestones and timelines.
- Preparing business plans and important documents (financial informations, legal documents, hiring documents).

Projects: W-YES, travel management platform | Velago, advance online travel platform.

PROSIA (PT. Pro Sistimatika Automasi, Jakarta, Indonesia)

12/2016 to 09/2017

Project Manager

- Developed project plan, scheduled and coordinated with clients to reach common agreement on timeline and deadlines.
- Defined the scope and solution design with technical team for the success execution of projects.
- Created project progress report to clients in a timely manner.
- Ensured customer requirements in line with the project scope of work.
- Worked with PM's of other projects to organize resources.

Clients: Alfamart (Approval Salary Online), Permodalan Nasional Madani (Document Management System), Sompo Insurance (Document Management System).

PROSIA (PT. Pro Sistimatika Automasi, Jakarta, Indonesia)

01/2016 to 12/2016

System Analyst & Pre-sales Consultant

- Assisted sales in the qualification of customer needs and requirements.
- Developed application mock-up based on customer requirements and performed demonstration.
- Developed solution by preparing and evaluating alternative business process solutions.
- Prepared functional specification document as a technical solution for production deployment.
- Created progress and issues report to the Manager in a timely manner.

Clients: Dinus Cipta Mandiri (Mobile Onsite Reporting), Honda-IKB (SPK online), Inna Hotel Group (Mobile Sales Prospecting), Alfamart (Approval Sallary Online), Pemerintah Kabupaten Bangka Tengah (Smart City), LAPAS (Visit Management System).

QISOFI (Qiwary Solusi Finansiaku), Bandung, Indonesia Software Development Manager

12/2014 to 12/2015

- Worked closely with Product Owner and Sales for understanding the system's functional and non-functional requirements.
- Monitored teams to ensure the product can deliver effectively and remain on target to meet deadlines.
- Provided software development plan that meets the future needs of markets.
- Evaluated software system in order to meets the specified requirements.
- Evolved the existing software system application and architecture in various areas as needed.
- Provided leadership and guidance to coach, motivate and lead team members to their optimum performance levels.

Clients: Bank Mayora (EDC & Sales Monitoring), Bank BTPN (CINTA DAMAI System - Mobile), MPM (Mobile Field Automation), AEON Credit Service (MIS-HP System).

QISOFI (Qiwary Solusi Finansiaku), Bandung, Indonesia

12/2013 to 12/2014

Business Analyst

- Identified opportunities for improving business processes through information systems and/or non-system driver changes.
- Assisted in the preparation of proposals to develop new systems and/or operational changes.
- Participated in software verification and software validation to determine whether an application meets specified requirements.
- Prepared reports by collecting, analyzing and summarizing information.
- Participated in user acceptance testing and testing of new system functionality.
- Provided technical assistance in training, mentoring and coaching professional and technical staff.

Clients: BII (Mobile Field Automation), Bank Sulsel (Loan Origination System), Asuransi CIGNA (Mobile Sales Reporting), Mandala Finance (Loan Origination System).

vITraining, Bandung, Indonesia

08/2013 to 11/2013

Software Quality Assurance

- Identified major system failure (bug, error).
- Ensured system meets data integrity standard.
- Performed documentation instructions for user.

INTERGATE, Sydney, Australia

5/2010 to 8/2012

Customer Services and IT Support

- Accountable for operating and monitoring mainframe and mid-range computer including peripheral equipments. Network performance monitoring and failure analysis.
- Troubleshooting and Operational correction procedure development.
- Costumer services related to Q&A and complaints.
- Produced daily report and input data.

PT. EXSA Internasional, Jakarta, Indonesia

1/2007 to 10/2009

Marketing and IT Staff (summary responsibility)

- Prepared presentation materials to be presented to various potential customers such as government department/ agencies.
- Performed market research and analyzed for potential customer.
- Designed and maintained company website.